<?xml version="1.0"?>
<menu>
  <header>
    <listname>AAE</listname>
    <lastlistupdate></lastlistupdate>
    <listversion>test</listversion>
    <exporterversion></exporterversion>
  </header>
  <game name="alienst">
    <description>Aliens: Tempest Alpha</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>4.3</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Alien Tempest alpha is a prototype of Tempest t is a shooter using wire-frame graphics. Each Wireway is taken on in turn, and has a network of lines guiding the movement paths of both yourself and the aliens. You remain on the outside and keep shooting as the aliens move towards you. Any that reach the outside are fatal to touch, thus limiting your range of movement greatly if 2 or more achieve this. Some aliens move sideways - in dealing with these, plan ahead allowing for the time your shots to take to travel.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="armora">
    <description>Armor Attack</description>
    <year>1980</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.2</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>You will be driving a jeep through a maze (Top-Down View). Of course such mazes , as we all know, are often not very safe when they are in a video game. Tanks and Helicopters will appear on the screen, you will have to shoot them before they shoot you. If you are hit by enemy fire you will lose a life.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="astdelux">
    <description>Asteroids Deluxe</description>
    <year>1980</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.2</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>A Deluxe version of Atari&apos;s original Asteroids, Asteroids Deluxe swaps the vector graphics for bitmaps. The basic gameplay is still the same: You fly your triangular ship around a space which wraps around the edges, filled with asteroids. Shooting the asteroids splits them into two smaller ones, until they are small enough to be destroyed. If you collide with an asteroid, you&apos;re dead, unless you activate your forcefield which will bounce the ship off the asteroids. Sometimes, a flying saucer flies through the screen, shooting everywhere. Additional asteroid shapes also show up, such as the blue target-seeking hexagons which split up into smaller triangular missiles.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="asteroid">
    <description>Asteroids</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>4.1</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Play the role of a spaceship pilot trapped in a gigantic asteroid cloud and pulverize incoming asteroids with the ship&apos;s photon cannon. When all asteroids are destroyed, the player can then move on to the next round. In addition to the asteroids, the player will also face an Alien Robot Saucer which shoots randomly across the screen.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="barrier">
    <description>Barrier</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Vectorbeam</manufacturer>
    <dev>Vectorbeam</dev>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <score>2.4</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Barrier is a maze arcade game using vector graphics released by Vectorbeam in 1979. In this very basic game, players move a small triangle around on the grid, while attempting to avoid the diamonds that are also moving around on the grid. Reaching the end of the grid teleports the player back to the front of the grid to gain points. The game is played on a 3x9 grid that is displayed at angle to make it appear to be in 3-D. The game was sold to Vectorbeam by</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="boxingb">
    <description>Boxing Bugs</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>2.6</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>This is kind of like a reverse of Star Castle. In the center of the screen is a player-controlled rotating cannon, enclosed within an octagon. The cannon shoots fireballs from one end and has a boxing glove on an extension arm on the other end. The octagon is a protective wall for the cannon. Fireballs and the boxing glove pass over the wall to targets outside.Bombs are randomly located outside the wall. Each bomb has a lite fuse. Three bugs are also randomly scattered outside the wall. The player&apos;s score, the number of cannons remaining, and the number of bugs that must be knocked out to complete the round are shown at the top of the screen.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="bwidow">
    <description>Black Widow</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.5</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Black Widow is an arcade game where you control the titular spider trying to protect its web. You move the spider around the web with the left joystick, and use the right joystick to shoot in different directions. Your web is being attacked by other bugs. You must either shoot them or avoid them. Avoiding them means leaving them to the Bug Slayer, a creature that&apos;s harmless to you, but is invulnerable and competes with you. After it defeats a bug, you can go after its prey to steal its points.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="bzone">
    <description>Battle Zone</description>
    <year>1980</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.8</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Battlezone is a first-person tank combat arcade game from Atari released in November 1980.[1] The player controls a tank which is attacked by other tanks and missiles. The game uses wireframe vector graphics on a black and white (with green and red sectioned color overlay) vector monitor. It was designed by Ed Rotberg, who designed many games for Atari Inc., Atari Games, and Sente.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="demon">
    <description>Demon</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Rock-ola</manufacturer>
    <dev>Rock-ola</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.5</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Demon is a monochrome vector arcade game from Rock-Ola that was created in 1982. The premise was that the player must fly his space shuttle around the screen collecting the crystals to keep the ship&apos;s laser powered.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="elim2">
    <description>Eliminator</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Gremlin</manufacturer>
    <dev>Gremlin</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.0</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>A top-down space shooter set within a bounded playfield, where the player maneuvers a ship using rotation, thrust and forward-firing controls (much like Asteroids or Space War). Each stage is populated by autmated drone ships (or by competing players), and dominated by the titular enemy: a moving, rotating space fortress surrounded by a lethal force field.This circular force field instantly destroys anything that smacks against it. Shots fired by the player (and the drones) are non-lethal: the target is simply kicked back across the playfield, bouncing off the walls. The exception is the enemy ship hidden inside the Eliminator - it can (and must) be destroyed by sneaking a shot through the structure&apos;s narrow opening. If this isn&apos;t done quickly enough, it will emerge and start pursuing the player with deadly fireballs.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="gravitar">
    <description>Gravitar</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.1</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>The evil being called Gravitar is out attempting to destroy the universe! With each galaxy he conquers he leaves behind extreme gravitational forces, a powerful, explosive reactor and deadly bunkers. Your job is to stop Gravitar by taking back the twelve solar systems located in four galaxies that are under his control! In each solar system there is a sun, an alien reactor base, and three to four planets. To free the solar system, you have two choices; either visit all of the planets and destroy all enemy bunkers, or activate the reactor at the core of the alien base and escape before it explodes. On each of the planets and the alien base, there will be strong gravitational forces to deal with; make sure you keep your ship in space, since a crash into the ragged landscape will be fatal! After a galaxy has been freed, you then automatically move on to the next galaxy which will be even more difficult to save. The game includes five different skill levels which vary in difficulty by supplying different amounts of ships to begin the game as well as different strengths of gravity</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="llander">
    <description>Lunar Lander</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Miscellaneous</genre>
    <score>3.3</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>In Lunar Lander The goal for the player is to land on the moon, by applying thrust to the lander in different directions. If the player hits the moon with too much velocity or lands on uneven terrain the lander will crash. When things tend to go wrong the player can press the abort button to quickly launch the lander back up again. The abort action and applying thrust costs precious fuel of which the player only has a limited amount. The player can rotate the lander to change his direction with more thrust. When the player gets closer to the moon the view zooms in to show a better view of the landing site.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="lunarbat">
    <description>Lunar Battle</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.1</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Lunar Battle is a prototype of Gravitar: The evil being called Gravitar is out attempting to destroy the universe! With each galaxy he conquers he leaves behind extreme gravitational forces, a powerful, explosive reactor and deadly bunkers. Your job is to stop Gravitar by taking back the twelve solar systems located in four galaxies that are under his control! In each solar system there is a sun, an alien reactor base, and three to four planets. To free the solar system, you have two choices; either visit all of the planets and destroy all enemy bunkers, or activate the reactor at the core of the alien base and escape before it explodes. On each of the planets and the alien base, there will be strong gravitational forces to deal with; make sure you keep your ship in space, since a crash into the ragged landscape will be fatal! After a galaxy has been freed, you then automatically move on to the next galaxy which will be even more difficult to save. The game includes five different skill levels which vary in difficulty by supplying different amounts of ships to begin the game as well as different strengths of gravity</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="meteorts">
    <description>Meteorites</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>4.1</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Meteorites is a clone of asteroids: Play the role of a spaceship pilot trapped in a gigantic asteroid cloud and pulverize incoming asteroids with the ship&apos;s photon cannon. When all asteroids are destroyed, the player can then move on to the next round. In addition to the asteroids, the player will also face an Alien Robot Saucer which shoots randomly across the screen.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="mhavoc">
    <description>Major Havoc</description>
    <year>1983</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.2</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>You are Major Havoc, a clone and leader of a band of clones. All from one, one from all, fighting for humanity... Long ago, the Vaxxian Empire overran the galaxy and enslaved most of humanity. Only a few scientists escaped. While the Empire has largely decayed, their robot-controlled space stations still keep humanity enslaved. You need to set the reactors of these stations to destruct. This game is part space shooter and part platformer. You begin the game in your ship, fighting through a space stations defenses. In the first couple levels, these are just drones you must shoot out of your way. In later levels, this defense is a maze of energy walls. Spinning drones create the walls. You can shoot the drones to prevent them from completing some walls. After that, you travel up through the maze, the walls of which are deadly to the touch. You can shoot a wall out of your way, however, this requires lots of shots and you are constantly moving forward. You can only move left and right and fire. After you have breached the defenses, you must guide your ship left and right to successfully land on the stations landing pad. Next, the game becomes a platform game. Your fire button is now a jump button. Following the direction of the red arrows, make your way to the reactor and touch it. You now have a limited time to make your way back to your ship and escape. You have a shield that can get you past an enemy but there is only one per station.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="omegrace">
    <description>Omega Race</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Midway</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.1</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>This is a remake of a Bally-Midway arcade game. You control a spaceship and shoot down the enemy Droid ships that attack you. Your ship must survive Droid-dropped mines too--but you can shoot them too. The last ship of the Droid flights goes into a spiraling pattern. There is no end to this game. Rather, it is a game in which you try to get the highest score, or complete the highest number of levels. You control a small triangle that is your ship. The ship can turn, move forward (with thrusters) and fire. Movement is one of the games challenges; once the ship is moving, it can only be slowed by turning the nose in the opposite direction and use the thrusters. While doing that, the ship is unable to fire toward anything it is in motion toward. Bouncing also comes into play during movement. When the ship hits the side of the screen, a wall of force appears, and the ship bounces. You don&apos;t have control over where the ship bounces, and must take time to regain control, before you run into an enemy ship and die.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="quantum">
    <description>Quantum</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Miscellaneous</genre>
    <score>3.0</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Using only a trackball, capture and destroy particles (Electrons, Nuclei, Photons, Positrons, Pulsars, Splitters and Triphons) by fully encircling them with your probe&apos;s tail. The number and speed of particles increases and the length of the probes tail decreases with each passing wave, increasing the difficulty of the task. Colliding with a particle destroys your probe. Circling multiple particles scores double points. On higher levels, the Nuclei join together forming bonds, lethal to your probe when red. A choice of starting levels (based on the previous level attained) is available at game start. A level is selected by circling it with the trackball. Quantum is unique for allowing the highest scoring player to sign his name freehand using the trackball. To achieve visually pleasing results requires considerable practice</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="redbaron">
    <description>Red Baron</description>
    <year>1980</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Flying</genre>
    <score>2.9</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Atari&apos;s Red Baron game is a one-player game with an X-Y or vector-generator monitor. The game depicts a first-person&apos;s view from a World War I biplane cockpit. The player&apos;s goal is to destroy as many biplanes, blimps, tanks, pillboxes, pyramids and buildings as possible. Players can maneuver their airplanes with the joystick control. Moving the joystick in its four directions creates a sensation of diving, climbing, or banking to the left or right.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="ripoff">
    <description>Ripoff</description>
    <year>1980</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.3</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Guard several fuel cells in the center of the screen from thieving pirates! As the pirates swoop in from the sides you will be charged with the duty to control a tank (Space ship) that can shoot down the pirates.The pirates can destroy you by using their own crafts to crash into you, or with short distance lasers. The moment the pirates drag off your last fuel cell you lose.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="solarq">
    <description>Solar Quest</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>5.0</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>In Solar Quest the player has to defend their star against incoming waves of enemy ships. Up to two players can play, taking turns. The player controls their ship from a top-down view. It is possible to rotate the ship 360° and exit/enter the screen at opposite edges. To defend themselves, players are equipped with rockets and nukes. Nukes are only available in limited supply. After firing a nuke, it can be detonated with a second push of the button, destroying a larger amount of enemies in its vicinity. Pressing the first button on the pad warps the player to a random position on the screen. After destroying an enemy ship, its survivor will float towards the sun. The survivor can either be shot or collected with the ship by flying through them. Scoring depends on the type of alien ship. Later waves bring more points when destroyed. The player can lose a life by crashing into an enemy ship or getting too close to the sun.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="spacduel">
    <description>Space Duel</description>
    <year>1980</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>2.9</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Space Duel is a sequel to Asteroids and Asteroids Deluxe. Instead of shooting lumpy asteroids, you are shooting colorful geometric shapes and several new enemies. There is also a bonus round where you can earn extra points. The two player game has two styles to choose from. &apos;Competitive&apos; allows you to shoot everything of the screen, including your opponent. It&apos;s all for one and that one is you. &apos;Team&apos; in the same except your shots will not harm the other player. You are working together to destroy the enemy.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="spacewar">
    <description>Space Wars</description>
    <year>1977</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>1.8</score>
    <player>2 Players</player>
    <story>Space Wars is an action game where two space ships battle each other. The game control is similar to Asteroids: you move by thrusting and rotating your ship left or right, you can fire in the direction you&apos;re facing, or enter hyperspace to randomly relocate your ship on the screen. If you can successfully destroy your opponent, a point is earned and the first player to reach 10 points wins the game. Besides the two ships, other obstacles are on the screen: a meteorite floats about randomly and in the center of the screen is a sun, both of which can destroy your ship. Two players can battle each other, or one player can battle the computer and several skill levels are available.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="spacfury">
    <description>Space Fury</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Sega</manufacturer>
    <dev>Sega</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>4.2</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>So! A creature for my amusement! Prepare for Battle! These are the words uttered by the alien commander upon starting a game of Space Fury. The gameplay is similiar to Asteroids in that you have one screen of space that wraps back on itself and your ship can only thrust and fire. However, whereas in Asteroids you faced pieces of rock that couldn&apos;t give chase, Space Fury instead provides alien vessels that will hunt you down. Each alien vessel starts in 4 pieces at diagonal corners which will try to join together. Shooting any of these pieces before is possible and will make things easier for your player. When one or more pieces reaches the center point, it combines with other pieces there and begins to fire upon and give chase to your vessel. There&apos;s only one screen of space, so your tactics are limited. However your vessel is not completely basic. Provided from the beginning are three superstructures, of which you can choose one, that provide additional firepower to your ship.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="speedfrk">
    <description>Speed Freak</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Vectorbeam</manufacturer>
    <dev>Vectorbeam</dev>
    <genre>Driving</genre>
    <score>1.7</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>This driving game is very intense. Your perspective is somewhat overhead and behind the hood of the car. A very fast game. In fourth gear you are moving extremely fast and control is difficult, making for exciting and hectic manuevers. The oncoming traffic is always the same car composed of 3-dimensional wireframe vector graphics -- very impressive and ahead of their time -- similar to the enemy tanks in Battlezone. The stationary objects are not as impressive and usually crudely rendered.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="starcas">
    <description>Star Castle</description>
    <year>1980</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>4.0</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>In this game you find yourself in a small ship opposed against a Star Castle. This fortress is a powerful turret placed behind three circular protective force fields. You will have to puncture through the force fields and make that demanding shot for the center. Each of the forcefields is made up of eight segments, each such segments take two hits to destroy. Of course it&apos;s not quite that easy... First small sparks will come out of the center trying to hit you. The turret in the center can also launch a very fast, and very accurate, laser at you. On top of that if you destroy a entire circular layer of force field it will regenerate along with another layer! This makes it impossible for you to stay in the same spot, as the layers rotate in opposite directions you will inevitable destroy one before breaching and destroying the center. Being hit by anything will cause the loss of one of your four lives, however if you hit the Forcefields you&apos;ll only bounce off.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="starhawk">
    <description>Star Hawk</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Flying</genre>
    <score>3.1</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>In StarHawk you zoom along a trench in a large sphere like object. All around space going vessels will fly past in set patterns. You will have the control of a target which you can move about the screen to blast those little fighters into oblivion, each will die in one hit. See how many you can shoot before you reach the end of the game.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="startrek">
    <description>Star Trek</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Sega</manufacturer>
    <dev>Sega</dev>
    <genre>Flying</genre>
    <score>3.9</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>There are five controls which need to be mastered, including a Tempest-like rotary knob for directing the course of the ship, a Phasers button which shoots limited range phasers, an Impulse button for forward motion at slow speed, a Photon Torpedo button that fires torpedoes capable of wiping out large portions of the galaxy and a Warp button that allows forward motion at super speed. The Photon Torpedo and Warp buttons are placed at an awkward position which may take some time to get used to. The game play involves a simulation of the powers and perils of piloting the Enterprise against The Klingon Empire. You have only one ship to command. If it is destroyed, the game is over. At the beginning of the game, you are given a certain number of shields and photons and during the game play, you can gain additional shields, photons, and warp power by docking with a Starbase. When your ship is hit, you lose a shield. If you run out of shields, the next hits will take out your photon torpedos, and next your warp power, and finally your ship, thus completing the simulation. There are six different enemies, including red, purple, and white Klingon ships, blue anti-matter saucers and the tricky yellow Nomad during special rounds, which plants dangerous space mines. The game has 40 different simulation levels, all of where you pilot the Enterprise and try your best to destroy all enemies to protect the Starbases throughout the galaxy.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="starwars">
    <description>Star Wars</description>
    <year>1983</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Flying</genre>
    <score>4.6</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Star Wars is a first-person shooter based around the final scenes of the original Star Wars film. It first appeared for arcade coin-operated machines and was subsequently converted to other gaming platforms. You take on the role of Luke Skywalker, aiming to destroy the Death Star. In the first phase you have to pass swarms of TIE Fighters, including dogfighting the one piloted by Darth Vader himself. In the second phase the station&apos;s surface is protected by laser towers, third involves attacking its weakest spot - the unprotected exhaust port - with proton torpedos. Your X-Wing starts with six shields, but more can be awarded for good performance. Complete the game and it loops back around at ever-increasing difficulty.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="sundance">
    <description>Sundance</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Miscellaneous</genre>
    <score>2.5</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Sundance is a puzzle arcade game using vector graphics released by Cinematronics in 1979. The game consists of two grids floating in a pseudo-3D space with small suns bouncing between them. The player scored points by capturing the suns as they made contact with the grids. The player also had a limited-use smart bomb button which would eliminate all of the suns currently bouncing between the grids. As the suns bounced, the grids would move closer and closer, making gameplay more difficult. The game ended when the grids fully converged.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="tacscan">
    <description>Tac/Scan</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Sega</manufacturer>
    <dev>Sega</dev>
    <genre>Flying</genre>
    <score>4.5</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Enemy airships are approaching your command base! You need to fly your five plane squadron into battle to defend it. You control a squadron of five ships at the bottom of the screen, your goal is to earn as many points as possible by destroying the various enemies which will be attacking. If one of the ships in your squadron is hit by enemy fire, it will be destroyed. The game ends when all five ships have been destroyed. As you progress through the game, you will occasionally have the chance to replenish missing ships. Everytime you complete a round by shooting ten enemies, an extra ship will float by on the screen. You can add this ship to your squadron by catching it in an empty space in the formation. Every time you complete four rounds, the game will advance to the next level with increased difficulty!</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="tailg">
    <description>Tailgunner</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Flying</genre>
    <score>2.6</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Tail Gunner is a monochrome vector arcade game created by Vectorbeam in 1979. The premise of the game is that the player is the tailgunner of a large space ship. Enemy spacecraft attack the vessel in groups of three, and the player must aim a set of crosshairs and shoot the enemies before they slip past the player&apos;s cannons. Because of the game&apos;s depicted viewpoint, instead of appearing to fly into the starfield, the stars move toward the center of the screen. In addition to shooting down the enemy ships, the player is also given limited use of a shield that can block ships from passing. The game ends when ten ships slip past the player&apos;s cannon. The game was sold as Tail Gunner II in a sit down cabinet[3] and its controls consisted of a single metal joystick with fire button integrated to the tip.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="tempest">
    <description>Tempest</description>
    <year>1980</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>4.3</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Tempest is a shooter using wire-frame graphics. Each Wireway is taken on in turn, and has a network of lines guiding the movement paths of both yourself and the aliens. You remain on the outside and keep shooting as the aliens move towards you. Any that reach the outside are fatal to touch, thus limiting your range of movement greatly if 2 or more achieve this. Some aliens move sideways - in dealing with these, plan ahead allowing for the time your shots to take to travel.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="vbreak">
    <description>Vector Breakout</description>
    <year>1999</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Clay Cowgill</manufacturer>
    <dev>Clay Cowgill</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>2.6</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Breakout is a Vecotr arcade game . In the game the player moves the paddle at the bottom of the screen and has to try and keep the ball from hitting the bottom. At the top of the screen there are stones which disappear when the ball hits them. Removing stones is worth points. The higher up the stone is located, the bigger its value. The player has several lives before he or she goes game over.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="vortex">
    <description>Vortex</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Atari</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>4.3</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Vortex is a prototype of tempest: Vortex is a shooter using wire-frame graphics. Each Wireway is taken on in turn, and has a network of lines guiding the movement paths of both yourself and the aliens. You remain on the outside and keep shooting as the aliens move towards you. Any that reach the outside are fatal to touch, thus limiting your range of movement greatly if 2 or more achieve this. Some aliens move sideways - in dealing with these, plan ahead allowing for the time your shots to take to travel.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc>Vortex is a prototype of tempest: Tempest is a shooter using wire-frame graphics. Each Wireway is taken on in turn, and has a network of lines guiding the movement paths of both yourself and the aliens. You remain on the outside and keep shooting as the aliens move towards you. Any that reach the outside are fatal to touch, thus limiting your range of movement greatly if 2 or more achieve this. Some aliens move sideways - in dealing with these, plan ahead allowing for the time your shots to take to travel.</crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="warrior">
    <description>Warrior</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Vectorbeam</manufacturer>
    <dev>Vectorbeam</dev>
    <genre>Fighter</genre>
    <score>3.4</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>The first one-on-one fighting game, Warrior was a 2-player overhead sword-fighting contest. Brilliant vector graphics and incredibly beautful backdrop and internal cabinet artwork made the game enthralling to watch, producing more complex images than Atari&apos;s vector hardware was capable of. Unfortunately, the Cinematronics vector system was also far less reliable. Most Cinematronics vector games are rare, and Warrior is rare among them.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="wotw">
    <description>War of the Worlds</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Cinematronics</manufacturer>
    <dev>Cinematronics</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>2.0</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>War Of The Worlds gameplay and graphics, and game was essentially a Space Invaders clone done using 3-D vector graphics. The player controls a tank object at the bottom of the screen and shoots towards the top of the screen at descending Tripods robots in a first person perspective. The player only has movement, cannon fire and shields to protect them from the Tripods&apos; lasers.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="zektor">
    <description>Zektor</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Sega</manufacturer>
    <dev>Sega</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>2.6</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>A fixed-screen, overhead shoot &apos;em up featuring a controllable ship with thrust and free rotation capabilities, similar to its predecessor Space Fury (and ultimately to Asteroids/Spacewar!). Your mission: infiltrate and recapture eight cosmic cities, presently held in thrall by a group of eight alien robots. Each of these mechanical antagonists (some male, some female) will taunt you in its synthesized voice as you approach its captured city. Once there, you must power through three waves of defense, consisting of drones and fighters - some enemies may be shielded, requiring multiple laser blasts to take out. Down the screen travel the indestructible Moboids, which come in three flavors (one sends ships into an uncontrollable spin, another bounces them away, and another destroys them on contact); the playfield doesn&apos;t wrap around, and bumping into the surrounding force-field will kick your ship back. Once the defenses are repelled, you will arrive at the city itself, where you&apos;ll face off against its robot conqueror, surrounded by concentric, rotating shields (a-la Star Castle). The robot will lob energy blasts at you as it tries to escape; if you manage to sneak a shot through the openings in its shields, your award is an extra life.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
</menu>
