<?xml version="1.0"?>
<menu>
  <header>
    <listname>Amstrad GX4000</listname>
    <lastlistupdate></lastlistupdate>
    <listversion>test</listversion>
    <exporterversion></exporterversion>
  </header>
  <game name="Barbarian 2 (Europe)">
    <description>Barbarian 2</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Ocean Software Ltd.</manufacturer>
    <dev>Palace Software, Ltd.</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>4.0</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Having thought you&apos;d dispatched the bald-headed evil wizard in the first adventure, you find that you must fight your way again to defeat Drax. This time you have the choice of the Barbarian or the curvaceous Princess to chop and slash your way through a plethora of various monsters – not humans this time – which are each defeated differently, against a wide selection of pretty backdrops which connect to form a labyrinth our heroes have to travel through to confront your enemy in the final showdown. Essentially, apart from the same look and feel (which is welcome), this is a different type of game from its predecessor; there&apos;s no two-player action (as in no head chops) and it thereby suffers for it. Incidentally</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Batman the Movie (Europe)">
    <description>Batman the Movie</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Ocean Software Ltd.</manufacturer>
    <dev>Ocean Software Ltd.</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>4.4</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Batman&apos;s nemesis, the Joker, is up to his evil tricks again. You must chase the Joker through Gotham City, in five levels of platforming and driving action. The game starts with you chasing Jack Napier through a chemical factory and cornering him so that he falls into a vat and becomes the Joker. You must then escape in the Batmobile to the Batcave and discover which objects contain the Joker&apos;s deadly chemical, Smilex. Once that&apos;s done, you go back on to the streets, and finally, pursue the Joker to Gotham Cathedral. The graphics and music are both up to Ocean&apos;s high standards, although the second level is infuriatingly difficult; I&apos;ve never been able to pass it without cheating</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Burnin&apos;&apos; Rubber (Europe)">
    <description>Burnin&apos;&apos; Rubber</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Amstrad PLC</manufacturer>
    <dev>Ocean Software Ltd.</dev>
    <genre>Driving</genre>
    <score>4.2</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>This is the game that every Plus owner has, because it comes free with the machine. It&apos;s an endurance race where you must stay on the track for as long as possible without running out of time, but first of all, you must qualify to settle your grid position. This game makes full use of the Plus&apos; extra abilities and has some beautiful, crystal-clear music on the title screen. The sky even changes from day to night to show your progress! It&apos;s touches like these that make this game better than others like it. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Copter 271 (Europe)">
    <description>Copter 271</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Loriciel SA</manufacturer>
    <dev>Loriciel SA</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>2.8</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>This is one of the less well known cartridge games, at least in the UK. The plot is certainly not original – it&apos;s the usual aliens have taken over the Earth story. You&apos;ve got the latest helicopter and have to destroy the aliens. The game is a standard vertically scrolling shoot-&apos;em-up where you fly your helicopter left and right, shoot &apos;planes and aliens, and collect some power-ups. The extra facilities of the Plus are used here to produce some nice graphics, but it&apos;s a shame that the game itself is rather dull. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Crazy Cars 2 (Europe)">
    <description>Crazy Cars 2</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Titus France SA</manufacturer>
    <dev>Titus France SA</dev>
    <genre>Driving</genre>
    <score>2.5</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>You&apos;re in a Ferrari F40 and are trying to smash a racket which is being run by some corrupt policemen. You have to race your car around four American states – Utah, Colorado, Arizona and New Mexico – and reach several destinations within the time limit. The police are on the loose, though! This game is much better than the original Crazy Cars, with excellent graphics and great Doppler effects when you&apos;re approaching police cars. There&apos;s also some really groovy digitised music to listen to on the title screen if you&apos;re playing the disc version of the game! The noise of your engine is OK, too, and it&apos;s a nice game with a lot of map-reading required</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Dick Tracy (Europe)">
    <description>Dick Tracy</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Titus France SA</manufacturer>
    <dev>Titus France SA</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>3.1</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>The famous comic strip detective must rescue his girlfriend, Tess Trueheart, who has been kidnapped by Big Boy Caprice and his gang. The game involves lots of shooting and beating up Caprice&apos;s henchmen, some of whom are heavily armed. Occasionally they will leave behind guns which you can collect, but their supply of ammunition is limited. The film that this game is based on was memorable for using only primary colours, and the graphics in the normal CPC version retain this theme, although they are blocky and poorly defined</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Enforcer (Europe)">
    <description>Enforcer</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Trojan</manufacturer>
    <dev>Trojan</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>4.5</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>It&apos;s the 1920s, the era of Prohibition, and the FBI are on the trail of a mob of gangsters who are manufacturing whisky. This is a three-level shoot-&apos;em-up which was only released on cartridge. It was intended to be used with the Trojan Phazer lightgun (and was one of only two such games released for the Plus version!), but thankfully it can be played with a joystick as well. In summary, you must shoot the gangsters to score points, but shooting innocent people (including unarmed gangsters) causes you to lose points. Once you have reached a certain number of points, you can go to the next level. The game is over when you are wounded once too often. The graphics are absolutely wonderful and it&apos;s fun to play for a while, but everyone has seen this type of game many times before. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Fire and Forget 2 (Europe)">
    <description>Fire and Forget 2</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Titus France SA</manufacturer>
    <dev>Titus France SA</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.2</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>More terrorist-busting antics await you in this disappointing sequel. The 3rd International Conference for Peace has been gatecrashed and a nuclear bomb has been placed inside the conference building. You control the new, improved Thunder Master II vehicle, with the ability to fire missiles and convert from a car to an airborne fighter. This time, there are five levels which become progressively longer; too long, in fact. You need to collect fuel, kerosene and missiles for the vehicle, and collisions and running out of fuel costs you one of your six lives. At the end of each level is a truck which you must destroy. The graphics are just as good as in the original game, and there&apos;s plenty of cool music to listen to as well. However, the very long levels make this a boring game with little variety. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Klax (Europe)">
    <description>Klax</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Domark Ltd.</manufacturer>
    <dev>Atari Games Corporation</dev>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <score>2.4</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Here&apos;s a great puzzle game which is a cross between Tetris and Connect 4. Coloured tiles come down a conveyor belt into a hole where you must create rows or columns of the same colour, which are called Klaxes. On each level, you&apos;ll be given a certain number of Klaxes or diagonals to make in order to complete the level. This is a stunning and original game with excellent graphics and two nice (but short) tunes, although it&apos;s pretty difficult. By the way</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Mystical (Europe)">
    <description>Mystical</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Infogrames Europe SA</manufacturer>
    <dev>Infogrames Europe SA</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>3.0</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>You&apos;re a young wizard who made a mistake in a magical formula and scattered all the spells and phials of his master, the Great Wizard. So you have to visit many parallel worlds to get them back from evil forces. Never mind the storyline, Mystical is a shoot-&apos;em-up – and a very good one. The graphics are gorgeous, the animation is smooth (though a bit sluggish at times) and the tune during the intro sequence is great. But it&apos;s a shame there are no sound effects in the rest of the game (lack of memory, perhaps?). Every time you collect a spell or a potion, you obtain a new power. There are many different characters and spells, which prevents boredom because the game is otherwise rather repetitive. With a greater variety in the design of the levels (and with sound effects!), Mystical could have been one of the very best CPC games</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Navy Seals (Europe)">
    <description>Navy Seals</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Ocean Software Ltd.</manufacturer>
    <dev>Ocean Software Ltd.</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>2.8</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>A helicopter crew of Navy SEALs, an élite American commando unit, has been kidnapped in Beirut by terrorists. A group of five of their comrades has been sent out to infiltrate the terrorists&apos; headquarters, rescue the hostages and destroy their stockpile of Stinger missiles. This is a platform game which involves brains as well as brawn. The terrorists are heavily armed, and one shot from them will kill you – so you have to sneak up on them, make sure they haven&apos;t seen you, then shoot them before they do the same to you. This game was only released on cartridge, but it uses the Plus&apos; extra facilities to good effect and is well worth playing, although be warned that it is very difficult; if it was a bit easier, I would give it a higher rating. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="No Exit (Europe)">
    <description>No Exit</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Tomahawk</manufacturer>
    <dev>Coktel Vision, MDO</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>2.0</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>No Exit is a side-view martial arts beat &apos;em up, similar in style to IK+. Each fight must be won within a time limit. You can specify your character&apos;s ability quite precisely, trading off Vivacity against Efficiency and Resistance against Strength. Your character has a special destructive mode, which can be accessed 3 times This turns the character into a monster (corresponding to the opponent you are fighting against) and increases the level of damage you can inflict.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Operation Thunderbolt (Europe)">
    <description>Operation Thunderbolt</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Ocean Software Ltd.</manufacturer>
    <dev>Taito Corporation</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>1.6</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>More hostages have been kidnapped, but this time they&apos;re being held deep in the African jungle. Firstly, you have to travel to the enemy&apos;s ammunition depot before going to the hideout where the hostages are being kept. Next, you must get into your boat and sail to the enemy HQ, where the final confrontation awaits. The game features a novel restarting system, where the number of continues you get depends on how well you&apos;re doing, although I&apos;m not sure this is entirely a good thing. It is a difficult game with more enemies on the screen at once, and worse, you can&apos;t see who you&apos;re firing at! The scrolling isn&apos;t very good either, and the graphics on the normal CPC version are horrible at times</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Pang (Europe)">
    <description>Pang</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Ocean Software Ltd.</manufacturer>
    <dev>Mitchell Corporation</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>3.8</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Travel across 17 nations and burst balloons as you go! There&apos;s not much of a plot to this game, but each level is divided into three screens, and you have to use a harpoon to blast the balloons. However, they will divide into two smaller balloons, and the same thing happens if you burst these balloons! If you&apos;re not careful, you&apos;ll have dozens of tiny balloons bouncing about and you&apos;ll lose one of your six lives. This is a really simple and addictive game, and it&apos;s one of the very few games around that makes full use of the Plus&apos; extra facilities. If it was that little bit easier, I would probably have given this game the full ten marks. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Panza Kick Boxing (Europe)">
    <description>Panza Kick Boxing</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Loricel</manufacturer>
    <dev>Futura</dev>
    <genre>Boxing/Sports</genre>
    <score>3.8</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>The press is unanimous: the best simulation to date! Two years work were barely sufficient to digitize all the blows, falls, foils and to recreate more than 120 combat positions. Produced with the exceptional assistance of Andre Panza, three times world Kick Boxing champion and three times European French boxing champion, this incredible simulation will bring you into the boxing world at the very highest level.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Plotting (Europe)">
    <description>Plotting</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Ocean Software Ltd.</manufacturer>
    <dev>Taito Corporation</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>2.1</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Here&apos;s a cute puzzle game which was only released on cartridge. On each level, you have to clear a pile of blocks from the screen by matching blocks together. You control an egg-like creature that can only move vertically and which can be positioned to allow the block to bounce off the walls of the screen, and hit the appropriate blocks in the pile. It&apos;s not easy to explain the rules, but if you have a few goes, you&apos;ll learn them quickly. You don&apos;t have to clear all the blocks, though; when you&apos;ve cleared enough, you can qualify for the next level. The game exploits the extra graphical facilities of the Plus machines, the music is really good as well, and there&apos;s also a two-player option which allows both players to play simultaneously. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Pro Tennis Tour (Europe)">
    <description>Pro Tennis Tour</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Ubisoft</manufacturer>
    <dev>Ubisoft</dev>
    <genre>Sports/Tennis</genre>
    <score>4.0</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Endorsed by famous tennis player, Jimmy Connors, this game offers tournament and single play on multiple court types.Using crosshairs, aim your ball to the other side of the court and hope you hit where you want. If you are lucky, you might even score an Ace. If not, you will need to be ready to return your opponent&apos;s return. Run back and forth as you try to keep hitting the ball over the net until your opponent misses, or you do. When you hit the ball, you will want to attempt changing the direction and speed of the ball to throw your opponent off balance. This is the real challenge of any tennis game.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Robocop 2 (Europe)">
    <description>Robocop 2</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Ocean Software Ltd.</manufacturer>
    <dev>Ocean Software Ltd.</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>4.5</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Robocop is back to clean up the streets of Detroit again, to close down the facilities that produce the addictive drug Nuke, and ultimately face his nemesis, Robocop 2. Seven levels of platforming and shoot-&apos;em-up action await you in this game, which was only released on cartridge. First of all, let me say that no game demonstrates the extra features of the Plus and GX4000 machines better than this one; the scrolling is extremely smooth, and hardware sprites and the many extra colours available are used to great effect. It looks and feels like a 16-bit game! However, it is very difficult indeed, although if you persevere and don&apos;t lose your temper, you will eventually learn the full layout of the first level. If it were a bit easier, I would have no hesitation in giving full marks to this game – but it&apos;s not to be. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Skeet Shoot (Europe)">
    <description>Skeet Shoot</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Trojan</manufacturer>
    <dev>Trojan</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>4.5</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Skeet Shoot is a bloodless shooter in which you have to blast clay pigeons out of the sky</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Pinball Magic (Europe)">
    <description>Super Pinball Magic</description>
    <year>1991</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Loricel</manufacturer>
    <dev>Loriciel</dev>
    <genre>Pinball</genre>
    <score>3.6</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Put a flipper in your console! This super pinball simulation will really make you tilt with pleasure! With its 12 levels, some of which are break outs, with plenty of bonuses and extra balls, SUPER PINBAL MAGIC is a must for all GX4000 and CPC+ owners!!</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Switchblade (Europe)">
    <description>Switchblade</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Gremlin Graphics Software Ltd.</manufacturer>
    <dev>Core Design Ltd.</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>3.3</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>The Fireblade, sacred symbol of the ancient Switchblade clan, has been smashed into 16 pieces by the evil Havoc - but they say that a Hiro can save it, and as Hiro, you must retrieve the 16 pieces and restore your people&apos;s pride. The gameplay is platform and ladders based, set both inside and outside. The layout of the territories becomes visible as you progress, and they can contain bonus weapons and secret rooms. Unlike the sequel you start without weaponry, and this is gained directly, rather than you collecting coins and trading them at shop sections. Holding down fire progressively builds up your fighting power.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Tennis Cup 2 (Europe)">
    <description>Tennis Cup 2</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Loricel</manufacturer>
    <dev>Loriciel</dev>
    <genre>Sports/Tennis</genre>
    <score>3.7</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>This is Loriciel&apos;s second tennis game for the CPC, and it&apos;s a pretty good one as well. Although you can&apos;t play in any tournaments, the game allows you to customise the abilities of both yourself and your opponent in several areas – namely service, forehand, backhand and volleys. You can also choose whether to play on a cement, clay or grass court. The game uses a split-screen technique which shows the view of the court from both ends, which is very useful in two-player mode, where both players have a clear view of their own end of the court. Although the graphics lack colour – and the colour schemes that are used have not been chosen well – the animation of the players is excellent, and after a few practice sessions, it&apos;s a very playable game as well. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Tin Tin on the Moon (Europe)">
    <description>Tin Tin on the Moon</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Infogrames Europe SA</manufacturer>
    <dev>Infogrames Europe SA</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>3.6</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Tintin and his friends, Captain Haddock and Professor Calculus, are on a rocket heading for the Moon, but Colonel Boris has sabotaged the rocket and has planted several bombs. The game consists of five stages. In each stage, you first have to move the rocket and dodge meteors while collecting red and yellow balls, and then, as Tintin, defuse the bombs, put out the fires that Boris is creating, and capture Boris. This is actually very easy, and it won&apos;t be long before you complete the game. The introductory sequence is the best bit of the game, actually!</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Wild Streets (Europe)">
    <description>Wild Streets</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Titus Ltd.</manufacturer>
    <dev>Titus Software Corporation</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>2.5</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>The head of the CIA, John Steven, has been kidnapped, and you have been sent to rescue him. You also have a companion in the form of a panther called Black Virgin – although as you&apos;ll find out, he (she?) is of almost no use! There are five levels, each one filled with gang members to beat up, but you can simply jump over them to the next screen without having to fight them. The only criminals you will need to kill are those on the last screen of the level, and you can use your gun to dispose of them easily. Once you&apos;ve rescued Mr. Steven, you must retrace your steps. The graphics and music are both of a high standard, but it&apos;s far too easy to complete</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="World Of Sports (Europe)">
    <description>World Of Sports</description>
    <year>1990</year>
    <rating>ESRB - E (Everyone)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Epyx</manufacturer>
    <dev>Epyx</dev>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <score>2.8</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>Four international events of death defying skill and endurance. Cliff Diving, Slalom Skiing, BMX Bike racing and Surfing from the masters of computer sports....EPYX.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
</menu>
