<?xml version="1.0"?>
<menu>
  <header>
    <listname>Bally Astrocade</listname>
    <lastlistupdate></lastlistupdate>
    <listversion>test</listversion>
    <exporterversion></exporterversion>
  </header>
  <game name="280 Zzzap+Dodgem (USA)">
    <description>280 Zzzap+Dodgem</description>
    <year>1978</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Bally Midway</dev>
    <genre>Driving</genre>
    <score>3.7</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>280 ZZZAP/DODGEM 2001: Two different high-speed car races demand quick response and raw courage. Enter your racing time into the computer - floor the accelerator - and go for speed and distance. 280 Zzzzap challenges you to hold a road filled with dangerous hairpin turns! Dodgem puts you up against other cars driven by the computer. The sharper your driving skills, the more mileage you&apos;ll get. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Amazing Maze+Tic Tac Toe (USA)">
    <description>Amazing Maze+Tic Tac Toe</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Dave Nutting Associates</dev>
    <genre>Multiplay</genre>
    <score>2.9</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Amazing Maze is a port of Midway&apos;s arcade game with the same name. This version can be played by one or two players and the numbers of wins needed is chosen before starting out. There are also three difficulty levels to choose from that affects the intricacy of the maze. Like in the arcade game the maze is randomly generated before every game. Tic-Tac-Toe is a digital adaptation of the pen and paper game. It can be played by one player against an AI or between two human players. Like in the other game on the cartridge the number of wins required is chosen before playing begins.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Artillery Duel (USA)">
    <description>Artillery Duel</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Astrocade</manufacturer>
    <dev>Perkins Engineering</dev>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <score>2.6</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>In this two player game each player controls an artillery gun set in a mountain landscape with the goal of destroying the other player. Players take turns firing at each other; on each turn you have a limited amount of time in which the barrel angle and powder level can be set in order to control the direction and distance of the shot. When deciding on your shot, you will need to take the current conditions into account, which includes wind speed/direction and any mountains that may get in your way. Successfully destroying your opponents gun will earn you a point, and the first player to reach the set number of points wins the game. There are multiple skill levels available which set the amount of time you have to make a shot.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Astro Battle (USA)">
    <description>Astro Battle</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Bally Midway</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.4</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Astro Battle is a Space Invaders clone arcade game released by Bally Manufacturing in 1978 for the Bally Astrocade arcade system. The aim is to defeat waves of aliens with a laser cannon and earn as many points as possible.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Bally Pin (USA)">
    <description>Bally Pin</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Dave Nutting Associates</dev>
    <genre>Pinball</genre>
    <score>3.0</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>Bally Pin is a pinball game featuring two different tables. The game is played with two joysticks, with one controlling the two left flippers and the other controlling the two to the right. The game can be played by up to four players who take turns until all player have used up all of their five balls. The aim is simply to get the highest score. The two tables are similar but with slightly different layouts and both feature six bumpers (lit or unlit), drop targets, upper kicker targets and a spinner. The ball is meant to react as a real ball would when struck by a flipper with the speed and angle of it being affected by where on the flipper it is hit. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Biorhythm (USA)">
    <description>Biorhythm</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Astro Home Arcade</dev>
    <genre>Rhythm</genre>
    <score>2.1</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Enter your birthdate and watch as the computer calculates your physical, emotional and intellectual cycles. The screen displays your highs, lows and critical days. This program can be great fun at parties. Biorhythm can help you develop a new awareness of your moods and personal interaction with the world</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Blackjack+Poker+Acey-Deucy (USA)">
    <description>Blackjack+Poker+Acey-Deucy</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Bally Midway</dev>
    <genre>Casino</genre>
    <score>3.4</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>Three all-time card game favorites! The computer stakes you to a thousand dollars and then it&apos;s either get rich quick or down the tubes. Authentic 52 card action! For example, in Blackjack you can double down or split, and five cards under 21 is an automatic winner. The computer does the dealing and keeps track of the money. Up to 4 players.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Blast Droids (USA)">
    <description>Blast Droids</description>
    <year>1983</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Esoterica</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>2.8</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Blast Droids is an action-game, in which the player has to destroy all of the hostile droids in each level. The ship steers like the one in the quite popular game Asteroids.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Brickyard+Clowns (USA)">
    <description>Brickyard+Clowns</description>
    <year>1978</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Dave Nutting Associates</dev>
    <genre>Breakout</genre>
    <score>3.4</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>This cartridge consists of two games: Brickyard and Clowns. Both games can be played by one to four players.-Brickyard is a clone of Breakout. It is almost identical to the original game but differs in that the ball moves in a trajectory and not in a straight path. The game can be played in four different difficulties that alters the speed of the ball as well as the size of the paddle. In a multiplayer game it&apos;s possible to choose different difficulties for each player. Clowns is a port of the arcade game with the same name.The number of balls or clowns available can in both games be selected from 1 to 99.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Candyman (USA)">
    <description>Candyman</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>L&amp;M Software</manufacturer>
    <dev>L&amp;M Software</dev>
    <genre>Maze</genre>
    <score>3.4</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Who plays tricks on the Candyman: This factory is in a mess since the two jokers have scattered life savers all over the floor. The Candyman must eat them up as quickly as possible while avoidingthe jokers. Be careful the jokers will get their buddies, the gremlins, to help them keep the life savers</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Checkers+Backgammon (USA)">
    <description>Checkers+Backgammon</description>
    <year>1985</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>New Image Software</dev>
    <genre>Board Games</genre>
    <score>2.8</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>A dual cart with the old classic board games of checkers or backgammon both can be played with 2 players or player Vs Cpu </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Conan The Barbarian (USA)">
    <description>Conan The Barbarian</description>
    <year>1985</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Dave Carson Software</manufacturer>
    <dev>Dave Carson Software</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>3.0</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>In Conan the Barbarian ! you play as the Cimmerian barbarian Conan your objective is in to slay various monster throughout the levels, Should a monster touch Conan, he will lose his stamina and Once all of Conan&apos;s stamina is gone, you lose the game.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Cosmic Raiders (USA)">
    <description>Cosmic Raiders</description>
    <year>1983</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Astrocade</manufacturer>
    <dev>Action Graphics, Inc.</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.6</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Cosmic Raiders is a side-scrolling shoot &apos;em up similar to Defender. Like in that game the player&apos;s space ship can move both left and right and there is also a radar showing the locations of enemies. The game takes place in the alien sector Larkin and the player&apos;s objective is to defend a planet under attack while also collecting energy sources from an evil alien race called the Larkins. In every level four bombs are dropped along with a number of fighters to ensure the bombs reach the surface of the planet. The objective of the game is simply to clear all the enemies and get the highest score possible. For every two bombs destroyed an energy star that the player can collect will appear. By picking it up the player&apos;s ship is energized with an invincible energy shield. Once all enemies have been cleared from one level the game moves on to the next.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Dog Patch (USA)">
    <description>Dog Patch</description>
    <year>1980</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Bally Midway</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.3</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Dog Patch is a two-player Skeet-Shoot type game in which players accumulate points by bouncing the target can between each player.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Football (USA)">
    <description>Football</description>
    <year>1978</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Dave Nutting Associates</dev>
    <genre>Sports/Football</genre>
    <score>3.2</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>Football is an early attempt at simulating the American sport. The game is played from a top-down perspective and features two unnamed teams, one blue and one yellow. When starting out the offense first gets to choose which of five plays to be used. After that the playing field will be displayed and after the ball has been snapped the player controls the quarterback with the joystick. By pressing the trigger a throw is made and the flight of the ball depends on the angle of the quarterback&apos;s arm which is controlled with the knob on the controller. After the pass has been made offense gains control of the ends by using the joystick. The defense uses the joystick to control the patterns of the cornerbacks. The ball carrier is considered tackled when making contact with any other player on the field.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Galactic Invasion (USA)">
    <description>Galactic Invasion</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Astrovision</manufacturer>
    <dev>Astro Home Arcade</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.8</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>Alien ships come at your missile launcher from every direction. They peel off from their formation singly or in groups of twos or threes. The more aliens you destroy, the more of their reinforcements attack. Each ship is piloted by a highly skilled captain capable of maneuvering with incredi- ble agility. Realistic sounds add to the intensity. Up to 4 players. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Galaxian (USA)">
    <description>Galaxian</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Bally Midway</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>4.2</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Up to four players can compete in this home version of Namco&apos;s well-known Galaxian coin-op. Options include a choice of four levels of difficulty and the ability to set the number of cannons given to each participant. As most arcaders already know, Galaxian is a sort of son of Space Invaders. Gamers move a laser cannon horizontally and fire upward at a swarm of insectoid creatures. Periodically, a trio of invaders peels off from the main body of attackers to sweep down and across the playfield, spraying the ground below with deadly bombs. The aliens are a lot easier to hit while they&apos;re still in formation, but better players will always withhold fire until some begin to swoop. An attack is worth twice as much when it is zapped in the midst of a dive-bombing run. Galactic Invasion&apos;s graphics are nice and colorful, but they don&apos;t quite match the artistic detail of the drawings used in the coin-op machine. The insects&apos; wings, for example, are not visible in the home program. The play-value, however is outstanding. The pistol-grip design of the Astro Arcade controllers give players excellent control over on-screen movement. The action sets a blistering pace that packs all the excitement of the arcade original. A Strategy depends on a combination of the skill of the player and the level of difficulty selected. In the easier versions, better marksmen will definitely want to wait until the insects make their move before lifting a finger to take them out. At the higher difficulty settings, Galactic Invasion is just plain murderous. Deadly aliens streak across the screen to ram the defending cannon and are capable of dropping a dozen bombs in one pass. Only the top gunners should sit back and wait for the bugs to make the first move. If they so much as twitch, blast &apos;em immediately. Once a three-insect group begins a sweep, all but the super-shots are virtually assured of being one life down by the time the maneuver is completed. The aliens always break formation from the sides. Therefore, a wise arcader will begin to attack from either the extreme left or right side of the playfield. That way, you&apos;ll have a good chance to eliminate the invaders before they come barreling down the screen at your gun. Galactic Invasion is one of the first cartridges Astrovision has released since acquiring the Professional Arcade from Bally. It is exactly the kind of well-conceived entry that should get all home arcaders to sit up and take notice of the revived system.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Grand Prix+Demolition Derby (USA)">
    <description>Grand Prix+Demolition Derby</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Astrovision</dev>
    <genre>Driving</genre>
    <score>3.1</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>Four challenging courses in race car driving excitement! Jockey for position at Le Mans or go for broke on a dangerous rally track! There&apos;s a constant trade-off between speed and maneuverability! Varying skill levels upgrade the challenge and the fun. Here is all the excitement of formula-style racing! The competition gets hotter as players improve their skills! 1 or 2 players. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Gunfight+Checkmate+Calculator+Scribbling (USA)">
    <description>Gunfight+Checkmate+Calculator+Scribbling</description>
    <year>1977</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Bally Midway</dev>
    <genre>Multiplay</genre>
    <score>3.3</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>4 programs built into the astrocade, first was a Calculator for all your mathematical needs, then there was Scrillbling for you artistic needs,also Checkmate a chess game to challenge your friends or cpu at. And then we Gunfight for a great shootout in the wild west.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="I.C.B.M. Attack (USA)">
    <description>I.C.B.M. Attack</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Spectre Systems</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>2.7</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>In I.C.B.M. Attack cities are being invaded by by alien craft hail your missin is to shoot them down before they destroy your city.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Incredible Wizard (USA)">
    <description>Incredible Wizard</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Astrovision</dev>
    <genre>Maze</genre>
    <score>3.3</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Challenge the Incredible Wizard and his creatures in their own environment: treacherous dungeons! Slip through the magic door to the other end of the dungeon, but prevent the super monster from escaping through it. Shoot the Incredible Wizard and experience the tremor of the entire dungeon as his magic wavers. Become a Worlord and play Worlord Dungeons - even go all the way to the PIT. Fantastic sounds and bonus plays make the Incredible Wizard just like coin-op games!</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Letter Match+Spell &apos;N Score+Crosswords (USA)">
    <description>Letter Match+Spell &apos;N Score+Crosswords</description>
    <year>1978</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Astrocade</manufacturer>
    <dev>Bally Midway</dev>
    <genre>Tabletop</genre>
    <score>2.8</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>Three different games will improve your vocabulary and reinforce spelling skills. Letter Match! Pair letters randomly selected by the computer. Spell &apos;N Score! Create as many words as you can from letters generated at random by the computer. Crosswords! The computer gives you letters. You turn then into words. 1 or 2 players.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Ms CandyMan (USA)">
    <description>Ms. CandyMan</description>
    <year>1977</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>L&amp;M Software</manufacturer>
    <dev>L&amp;M Software</dev>
    <genre>Maze</genre>
    <score>3.4</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Real arcade action with joysticks, 1 or 2 players and 3 levels of difficulty. More Clan 20 screens, each faster than the one before. Full screen display in exquisite retail. Ms. Candyman must pick up all of the lifesavers as quickly as possible while avc ding contact with the Ghosts &amp; Goblins. During the first half of a screen the Ghc. or Goblins will try to catch you. During the 2nd half of a screen the Ghosts or Goblins will take up protective positions to keep you away from the life savers. Each cz tact costs Ms. Candyman 1 life and she will nose-dive head first off the bottom of thr clay field. A wrecker or ambulance will carry her off. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Muncher (USA)">
    <description>Muncher</description>
    <year>1983</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Esoterica</dev>
    <genre>Maze</genre>
    <score>3.7</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Muncher stars a little, yellow dot-muncher who works his way around to clear a maze of the various dots and fruit which inhabit the board. The goal is continually challenged by four ghosts, One touch from any of these ghosts means a loss of life for MuncherMuncher can turn the tables on his pursuers by eating oneof the four power pills located within the maze. During this time, the ghosts turn blue, and Muncher can eat them for bonus points. This only lasts for a limited amount of time, as the ghosts&apos; eyes float back to their center box, and regenerate to chase after Muncher again</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Pirates Chase (USA)">
    <description>Pirates Chase</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Astrocade</manufacturer>
    <dev>Astrocade</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>2.8</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Meet the game in the plain brown wrapper. Pirate&apos;s Chase is a two-player contest that may well prove highly habit-forming to videogamers. It really doesn&apos;t look like much, but its play mechanic certainly produces a bumper crop of close calls and thrilling confrontations.Using the joystick portion of the Astrocade controller, each player moves his on-screen symbol vertically, horizontally or diagonally across a rectangular playfield composed of regularly spaced dots. The result is something that might be called a maze-less gobble game, since passing over a dot removes it from the screen and adds its point value to the appropriate player&apos;s total. Periodically, special bonus prizes appear at random points on the screen (but always replacing an ordinary dot). These are generally worth 100 points multiplied by the level at which the game is then being played. After the combatants cycle through an array of trinkets and goodies, the game returns to the first bonus prize for another go-around.Besides racing against the other player to see who accumulates the greatest number of dots and bonus objects, both joystick wielders must always flee from the pirate. This nautical no-goodnik, symbolized by the traditional skull and crossbones, takes one of the player&apos;s precious lives whenever it catches up with the corresponding symbol on the playfield.The missing ingredient-- about the only one in an otherwise solid cartridge is the visual element. Pirate&apos;s Chase doesn&apos;t look all that attractive, though plain would be a better description than ugly. Let&apos;s hope that Astrocade owners have the sense to look past the wrapping to see the gem buried inside.If electronic game-lovers are able to unshackle themselves from the prejudices of this intensely graphics-oriented period in the hobby, their reward will be a first-rate action contest. Its non-stop play routine, although admittedly somewhat repetitive in longer rounds, is positively riveting.One of the key factors which does the most to build excitement during play is the (intentionally imprecise) steering. It is really quite difficult to steer a straight course, much less make sharp turns. As a result, both players frequently end up circling a particularly juicy bonus object like flies buzzing around a pot of honey.As must be the case with any game that includes an open playfield and a merciless robot attacker, strategy is fairly fluid in Pirate&apos;s Chase.In general, the best advice is to make as few turns as possible when scooping up all of the dots and prizes. That golden scoring opportunity occurs when the pirate has caught the other player and your symbol is still active. This is the time to concentrate on hitting the bonus objective.Pirate&apos;s Chase&apos;s dull visuals not-withstanding, offers the rare chance to compete head to head</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Red Baron+Panzer Attack (USA)">
    <description>Red Baron+Panzer Attack</description>
    <year>1978</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Dave Nutting Associates</dev>
    <genre>Multiplay</genre>
    <score>3.7</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>This cartridge consists of two war themed games: Red Baron and Panzer Attack. Both games are multiplayer only. Red Baron is played by two players while Panzer Attack can played by two to four players. Red Baron is a dogfighting game played from a side perspective on a single screen. Both planes start rolling on the ground and have to lift before crashing into a barn. Once in the air the planes can be moved in all directions and it&apos;s also possible to alter the speed. The aim is simply to get as many kills as possible before the time runs out. The time limit is chosen by the players before starting out. Panzer Attack is a tank game viewed from a top-down perspective. All player share the same single screen which has a few blockades for protections. The tanks can move in all directions and the aim of the game is simply to score points by destroying the other tanks. A battle ends when just one tank remains standing and the player with the highest score when all battle have been played wins. The number of battles can be chosen before starting out from 1-99.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Road Toad (USA)">
    <description>Road Toad</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Esoterica</manufacturer>
    <dev>Esoterica</dev>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <score>3.2</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>In Road Toad The object of the game is to direct Toads to the other side of a busy road while avoiding the hazards that come from the left and right.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Sea Devil (USA)">
    <description>Sea Devil</description>
    <year>1983</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>L&amp;M Software</manufacturer>
    <dev>L&amp;M Software</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.2</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>You must destroy the hoard of poachers as quickly as possible because each bit of food (the white abalone on the bottom) they get will cost you bonus score at the end of the screen. Beware, the poachers are releasing under sea mines to destroy you, avoid them by evasive action. Each contact your craft makes will cost you 1 ship. Level 1 pits you against octopi &amp; android divers. For each level that is cleared a new one will appear and the game speed will in-crease. Periodically Zardos will put additional kinds of his creatures in your path. This occurrs at level 2 with star fish added to the playfield, level 3 with jelly fish and level 5 with mechanical crabs. At level 7 Zardos&apos; sub will appear and begin firing cluster bombs at you. Additional levels will provide increased speed and more attrac-tion between you and your opponents. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Seawolf+Missile (USA)">
    <description>Seawolf+Missile</description>
    <year>1978</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Dave Nutting Associates</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.6</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>This cartridge consists of two games: Sea Wolf and Missile. Both can be played by one or two players. Sea Wolf is a port of the arcade game with the same name. Missile is based on the arcade game Guided Missile but differs in some ways. Like in the original game the aim is to shoot down targets (here only flying ones) with missiles but here the missiles do not descend back towards the ground after reaching the top. Instead the player here has to guide them on the way up. Another difference is that the player can move the missile base left and right before launching a missile.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Sneaky Snake (USA)">
    <description>Sneaky Snake</description>
    <year>1983</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>New Image Software</manufacturer>
    <dev>New Image Software</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.0</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>In Sneaky Snake: Each player starts with five shooters, utilized one at a time. The T.V. screen will present the player(s) with a field of multi-colored mushrooms. At the top of the screen will appear the Snake, who will begin his decent downward, meandering over, under and around the mushrooms as he moves closer to you! At the bottom of the playfield is your shooter, which you can maneuver left or right, and slightly up or down. Using the trigger, you must shoot the Snake before he makes contact with your shooter.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Soccer (USA)">
    <description>Soccer</description>
    <year>1985</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>ABC Hobbycraft</manufacturer>
    <dev>ABC Hobbycraft</dev>
    <genre>Sports/Soccer</genre>
    <score>2.8</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>Soccer a simple 4 player game of pass,dribble shoot,score. Try your hardest to beat the cpu or your friends in the match of the day, win,lose or draw your sure to have fun, come kick off.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Solar Conqueror (USA)">
    <description>Solar Conqueror</description>
    <year>1983</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Astrovision</manufacturer>
    <dev>Action Graphics, Inc.</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.5</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>Solar Conqueror is a top-down viewed shoot &apos;em up with multidirectional shooting and movement similar to Asteroids or Robotron. The war hungry DEMENS are threatening to wipe out the player&apos;s race with a radiation death ray and therefore the player has to conquer their solar systems.Each solar system consists of two or four planets and to conquer them all planets have to be defeated. In each screen a planet is located to the far right of the screen and from it various alien defenders will appear. To defeat the planet and move on to the next one the player has to kill all the enemies while avoiding getting hit by them. There are three different enemies: kamikaze combat ships, ground-to-air missiles and super fighting (killer) satellites. There are also asteroids floating around the planets that has to be avoided. Larger planets have stronger gravity which leads to the spaceship being harder control. The effect of the gravity increases as the ship gets closer to the planet.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Fortress (USA)">
    <description>Space Fortress</description>
    <year>1981</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Astrovision</manufacturer>
    <dev>Astro Home Arcade</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.6</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>Coin-op fans will instantly recognize this super fast-action arcade-style space shoot-&apos;em-up as Midway&apos;s Space Zap. Gamers command a centrally located command fortress capable of firing in any of four directions-- North, East, South and West. From those respective positions at the top, bottom and sides of the playfield emerge alien laser-cannons and the occasional, free-flying mystery ship. As the contest commences, these enemy intrusions are infrequent, appearing at a leisurely pace and waiting a good while before actually firing. Once a cannon fires its laser torpedo, the missile can be detonated by a burst from the player&apos;s fortress, and a second blast will be required to eliminate the cannon itself. Graphics in this Bob Ogdon (of Dave Nutting Associates) creation are crisp and convincing, but it&apos;s primary claim as a space action classic is as the world&apos;s fastest home blast-&apos;em-up sf videogame. Once the player has gotten the feel of the play mechanic, things really start jumping. The fortress is soon transformed into a whirling dervish of destruction, spinning crazily and spitting out flaming death. This is not the sort of game that arcaders will find themselves playing compulsively for hours. Wrists give out after about ten minutes of heavy duty action. Play sessions will be brief but intense. The most difficult obstacle players will encounter, aside from weakness of the flesh will be the UFO/mystery ship. Strategically, at all but the highest levels-- where it must be incinerated at the first opportunity-- play a waiting game. As in most space shoot-outs of a linear type (such as Space Invaders, Spacechase and Demon Attack) it&apos;s best to let the enemy come to you in preference to actively chasing after him. Sit patiently, but once the enemy strays into range, hesitate not. Perhaps the most manic space battle of all time, Space Fortress will leave you gasping. But you&apos;ll always come back for more.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Speed Math+Bingo Math (USA)">
    <description>Speed Math+Bingo Math</description>
    <year>1978</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Bally Midway</dev>
    <genre>Multiplay</genre>
    <score>2.5</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>If there was everany methods to make learning addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division fun, playing Speed Math and Bingo Math could be the answer.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Battle (USA)">
    <description>Star Battle</description>
    <year>1979</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Dave Nutting Associates</dev>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <score>3.2</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Star Battle is a space shooter based on the trench run sequence from the original Star Wars movie. The game is for one or two players and involves a battle between an X-Wing and a Tie Fighter, although since it doesn&apos;t carry a license they are not called that. The X-Wing is controlled by player one while the Tie Fighter is controlled by player two or the computer. Before starting out a maximum score (1-999) is entered and the player that first reaches it wins the game. A single hit is enough to bring down the enemy ship and it is worth one point.The game is viewed from a third-person perspective with a pseudo 3D representation of the trench. The colour of the trench changes constantly to illustrate the forward motion of the fighters. By moving the joystick up or down the fighters accelerate or decelerate which means they move to the top of the screen and decreases in size or move to the bottom and get larger. If one moves closer to the camera the other gets further away and vice versa</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Slope (USA)">
    <description>Super Slope</description>
    <year>1982</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Esoterica</manufacturer>
    <dev>Esoterica</dev>
    <genre>Sports/Skiing</genre>
    <score>3.1</score>
    <player>1 Player</player>
    <story>In this one-player game, the player directs his skier downhill, avoiding pine trees and large rocks by using the joystick to ski left or right across the slope. A quick tap on the joystick increases the skier&apos;s direction from straight to slightly angled; another tap increases the angle further; and another tap will have the skier doing a traverse. The same holds true for either direction. Squeezing the trigger will increase the skier&apos;s speed. </story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Tornado Baseball+Tennis+Hockey+Handball (USA)">
    <description>Tornado Baseball+Tennis+Hockey+Handball</description>
    <year>1978</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Bally Midway</manufacturer>
    <dev>Bally Midway</dev>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <score>2.9</score>
    <player>1-2 Players</player>
    <story>Four major sports games in one cartridge give you a super value! Extraordinary computer simulations of all the action BASEBALL:It&apos;s baseball like the Major leagues with players moving, bats swinging, crowds cheering and runners scoring. Points are earned by a runner crossing home plate, just as in a real baseball game. HANDBALL: This fast-paced action game keeps the players running. After the serve, take turns retrieving the ball which will bounce off the front and sides of the court. The first player to gain 21 points is the winner. HOCKEY: Score goals by firing the puck into your opponent&apos;s net. From the moment of the face off, the action is fast and furious, so prepare to respond quickly! TENNIS: Challenge your friends to a tennis match and play singles or doubles. Score points for every volley your opponent is unable to return.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
  <game name="Treasure Cove (USA)">
    <description>Treasure Cove</description>
    <year>1983</year>
    <rating>HSRS - GA (General Audience)</rating>
    <manufacturer>Spectre Systems</manufacturer>
    <dev>Spectrecade</dev>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <score>4.2</score>
    <player>1-4 Players</player>
    <story>Treasure Cove is an action game that takes place off a small island in the Caribbean where the player has to dive into the ocean and search for the treasure of a lost Spanish galleon. The action takes place on a single screen and the player starts out in a small boat at the top of the screen. At the bottom there are several pieces of treasure that has to be retrieved (one at a time) but the ocean is also full of fishes and other sea creatures that have to be avoided. Any contact with these (including the smallest of fishes) will lead to an immediate loss of life. A life is also lost if the player runs out of oxygen which means it&apos;s necessary to plan ahead since it&apos;s not possible to go back to the boat (and recharge the oxygen) empty handed. With the press of a button the player can move quicker but at a higher cost of oxygen. After clearing all treasure from the cove the game will move on to a new location with more valuable treasure but also with more fishes. The game can be played by one to four players in hot seat. Before starting out the number of lives for each player can be chosen from one to nine. There is also a tournament level mode where each player has four divers. This mode was meant for players who wanted to mail their high score to the developer for high score verification.</story>
    <enabled>Yes</enabled>
    <crc></crc>
    <cloneof></cloneof>
  </game>
</menu>
